<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Gordon Fontenot</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/feed.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Gordon Fontenot</name>
        <email>gordon@fonten.io</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2017-07-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Making Time for Side Projects</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/making-time-for-side-projects" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/making-time-for-side-projects</id>
    <published>2017-07-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have about a million things I’d like to do at any given moment. If I sit down and try to choose something to spend my time on, it’s fairly overwhelming. There are blog posts I could write, books I could read, movies and TV shows I could watch, or any number of ways I could continue my own education via videos or articles. And then there are the side projects. So so many side projects.</p>
<p>The problem with side projects is that you can’t complete them. No matter what you think, side projects aren’t done<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>. You might be able to finish reading a book or watching a run of a TV show, but you’ll never finish that “small” tool you’ve been meaning to write. There will <em>always</em> be something to improve, something to tweak, something to fix.</p>
<p>I decided a while ago to write my own microblog. This “small” app was supposed to serve two different purposes:</p>
<ol style="list-style-type: decimal">
<li>To take back ownership of my writing and host it under my own domain and in my own database.</li>
<li>To act as an excuse to learn <a href="https://www.yesodweb.com/">Yesod</a> so that I could start on my <em>real</em> side project.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/featureless-void">My microblog</a> is now 7 months old and has seen <a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/featureless-void/commits/master">133 commits</a> to master (at the time of this writing) and isn’t <em>close</em> to being “finished”. And this isn’t even the thing I <em>want</em> to work on as my side project. I’ve spent so much time working on The Small Thing that I’ve barely even <em>started</em> on The Real Thing.</p>
<p>So, presented with infinite things to do, an infinite amount of time that those things will take up, and a spectacularly finite amount of time to do them: how the shit do I actually get things done?</p>
<p>The solution I’m going to experiment with is to explicitly set aside a part of my week that I tend to otherwise “waste”<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>, and dedicate it to working on a side project. For me, this means Sunday mornings (before noon). I expect <em>most</em> of that time to be spent working on my main side project (a workout tracking app I’m currently calling Swole), but I’m also not going to stop myself from working on projects like <a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/featureless-void">my microblog</a>, <a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/dotfiles">my dotfiles</a>, or <a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/reflow">any</a> of <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/Argo">my</a> other <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/Runes">open</a> source <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/Swish">projects</a> if they should catch my interest that week. The important thing here is not necessarily the specific project I work on, but is instead to be strict with myself about stopping at noon and not letting that time spill over into the rest of the day, or the rest of the week. By limiting myself to this specific sliver of time, I hope to see myself be able to focus on my project when I need to, and ignore it during the rest of the week.</p>
<p>As an added bonus here, the short time frame <em>should</em> present itself well to learning (or implementing) small, specific bits of functionality. My hope is that these weekly experiments will easily translate into blog posts on the subject, which will help me improve my writing habits.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>See this post by Good Friend And Awesome Person Gabe Berke-Williams: <a href="http://gabebw.com/blog/2015/01/14/move-your-goalposts">Move Your Goalposts</a><a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>I firmly believe there’s no such thing as “wasted” time, just time that’s spent with a different set of priorities. See the venerable Merlin Mann’s post <a href="http://www.43folders.com/2009/04/28/priorities">Mud Rooms, Red Letters, and Real Priorities</a> for more on “priorities”.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Liftoff Spinoff</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/liftoff-spinoff" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/liftoff-spinoff</id>
    <published>2017-04-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-04-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>An iOS blogging workflow for static sites</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/an-ios-blogging-workflow-for-static-sites" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/an-ios-blogging-workflow-for-static-sites</id>
    <published>2017-02-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog is (at the time of this writing) a static website hosted on GitHub. It’s written in <a href="https://www.haskell.org/">Haskell</a> (using <a href="https://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/">Hakyll</a>), built on <a href="https://circleci.com/gh/gfontenot/website-source">CircleCI</a> when I push to <code>master</code>, and then deployed to <a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/gfontenot.github.com">GitHub Pages</a>. It’s a fairly complex process, but it’s a fun side project, and it’s automated enough to fit my needs.</p>
<p>However, because of all these moving parts, I never really nailed down a workflow for writing blog posts on the go. At the very least, I need access to Git in order to publish new posts. So I end up writing and publishing exclusively on my laptop, where I have access to git and vim and my usual dev environment. This deficiency has (I believe) led to the low level of activity on this blog. I only really write things when I have a lot of time and am actively sitting in front of a computer. This means that if inspiration somehow strikes, I tend to not follow up on it. It also means that I’ll start posts, but never finish them because I walk away from my computer.</p>
<p>I’ve been thinking about this deficiency a lot lately, because I’ve been spending a lot of time working on my <a href="https://github.com/gfontenot/featureless-void">microblog</a>, where I see mobile posting as being a Must Have feature. I’m <em>probably</em> going to be using the <a href="http://micro.blog">micro.blog</a> iOS app for posting to that (once I write an API), but it got me wondering if there was a good app/reasonable workflow I was missing that would help me to be able to write longer form content on iOS.</p>
<h2 id="needs">Needs</h2>
<p>Let’s start with what I <em>need</em> from an iOS blogging solution. Turns out, they are fairly minimal:</p>
<h3 id="markdown-editing">Markdown editing</h3>
<p>This is should be obvious. All of my posts are written in Markdown, so I need some basic ability to write/edit markdown. This requirement basically boils down to “can write text in it”, because markdown is <em>designed</em> to be easy to write in plain text.</p>
<h3 id="new-file-creation">New file creation</h3>
<p>I need to be able to create new files, in addition to being able to edit existing ones. If I can’t start writing when I have that thought “I should write something about this”, the odds of me never writing that post go up dramatically. In addition, I’ll need to be able to create posts in a very specific location (<code>web/posts</code>, for my repo). I’ll <em>also</em> want to be able to create files with a specific format (downcased, normalized version of the title, with a prefix of the date). There’s a lot to consider here.</p>
<h3 id="pushing-to-github">Pushing to GitHub</h3>
<p>This is clearly the big one. If I can’t push to GitHub, I can’t publish. If I can’t publish, then what’s the point (other than, I suppose, getting my thoughts out of my head to publish later)? This is definitely going to be the sticking point for me.</p>
<h2 id="wants">Wants</h2>
<p>In addition to the bare minimum things I know I need, there are some things that would be super nice to have if possible:</p>
<h3 id="a-decent-editing-interface">A decent editing interface</h3>
<p>I think my ideal here is a full-screen interface with as little chrome as possible. Some markdown helpers are fine, but probably not too many.</p>
<h3 id="branch-support">Branch support</h3>
<p>Sometimes, I don’t want to just post to <code>master</code>, and would instead rather push to a branch so that I can open a PR for other people to review. I don’t do this <em>super</em> often (I don’t <em>blog</em> super often), but I’d like to have the option if I can.</p>
<h3 id="draft-management">Draft management</h3>
<p>I don’t know that I care <em>too</em> much about how drafts are handled, but I definitely want some way to handle them. I’d like to then be able to “promote” drafts to a “published” state. At that point, I’d want to either prepend today’s date to the file name, or update the date that the file name already had.</p>
<h3 id="multiple-repo-support">Multiple repo support</h3>
<p>I’d like to be able to use one workflow for my blogging, no matter what blog I’m writing for. For example, the <a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com">thoughtbot blog</a> source code is also hosted on GitHub, and works in largely the same way that this one does. If I could re-use my workflow/app to post to that blog, I might contribute there more frequently as well.</p>
<h3 id="file-templates">File Templates</h3>
<p>I need a pretty specific format for my YAML frontmatter for my posts. It’s not a <em>complex</em> format, but I do forget what the format is literally every time I go to write a post. Automating that away would be a huge time saver for me.</p>
<h2 id="existing-solutions">Existing solutions</h2>
<p>The first thing I did was look for an existing application that fit my needs. Unfortunately, this is all pretty hard to search for, so I didn’t turn up much. But I <em>did</em> find <a href="https://appsto.re/us/rk9UM.i">OctoPage</a>. It’s an iOS app that authenticates with GitHub and lets you write/publish new files. It even lets you choose a different repo to look at, although the UI around this is pretty clunky.</p>
<p>However, it’s actually impossible for me to give OctoPage a fair shot. The developers decided to hardcode the paths for drafts and posts according to Jekyll’s conventions. And since I’m not following those conventions, it can’t find my posts or my drafts. Bummer. There’s almost definitely a market here for this exact app, but with configurable paths.</p>
<h2 id="lets-hack-something-together">Let’s hack something together</h2>
<p>I think that, given unlimited time, I would probably build a solution that hits all of the points above. But I have very little time as is, so instead of spending untold hours building something completely custom, let’s see if there are existing <em>pieces</em> that I can use to make up the whole.</p>
<h3 id="github">GitHub</h3>
<p>The first step is the most important. I need to be able to push commits up to my repo. After some looking, I’ve settled on <a href="http://git2go.com/">Git2Go</a> as a GitHub app. The UI is really nice, it will allow me to jump around between repos/branches at will, and even do some light editing if needed. Critically, it also has pretty robust <a href="http://faq.git2go.com/2016/01/24/How-to-use-URL-schemes.html">URL scheme support</a>, that I’ll be able to use with a markdown editor in order to be able to publish posts.</p>
<p>Since this is doing so little, there’s not really too much setup that needs to happen here. Once I’m authenticated with GitHub, I just pull down my <code>website-source</code> repo and I’m ready to go.</p>
<h3 id="writingeditingpublishing">Writing/editing/publishing</h3>
<p>I looked at a few apps for this, and ended up with a bit of a compromise between power and usability. What I’m looking for at this level is a nice editor that makes it easy to quickly create posts, not <em>too</em> painful to edit them, and simple to send them over to Git2Go for publishing.</p>
<p>My first stop was to check out <a href="http://1writerapp.com/">1Writer</a>. It has a really nice distraction-free UI and you can create custom actions to perform with/on your documents. To top things off, you can even set Git2Go as a file location, which lets you open up files from your git repo <em>directly</em> in 1Writer.</p>
<p>I was able to create a neat URL scheme action for 1Writer that would let me send the current file to my posts directory in Git2Go. They also allow people to publish/share their actions, <a href="http://1writerapp.com/action/8ae98">so here you go</a>. You’ll almost definitely want to modify the path if you choose to use it, but its a reasonable starting point.</p>
<p>I <em>really</em> wanted to stop there. It was almost perfect. I wish I <em>could</em> use 1Writer. But ultimately, it wasn’t quite powerful enough. So in the end, I settled on <a href="http://omz-software.com/editorial/">Editorial</a>.</p>
<p>Editorial is almost absurdly powerful. Instead of single actions you can perform (like 1Writer has), Editorial can handle workflows built from any number of arbitrary actions. And where the actions in 1Writer are fairly simplistic (consisting of a single input and a single output), Editorial workflows can contain variables, loops, conditionals, you name it. They can use editor commands, URL schemes, or even arbitrary python code (1Writer has JavaScript actions). This means we can do things like formatting today’s date and prepending it to the blog post file name before we send it to Git2Go so that the publish date is set properly.</p>
<p>As with 1Writer, Editorial has a website set up to share these workflows, so <a href="http://www.editorial-workflows.com/workflow/5819211662229504/5C5rAd6f54c">here’s mine</a>.</p>
<p>In addition, these workflows can be used to create custom file templates. We can actually use custom text input to get the name of the blog post, then use that name to generate a downcased, normalized file name. Then we can add that original name to the yaml frontmatter for the post. Really crazy stuff. Unfortunately, I can’t for the life of me figure out how to share these templates, so you’ll just have to take my word for it.</p>
<p>Finally, Editorial’s preview feature lets you custom the HTML, and you can even link external CSS. So I’ve actually set up my preview theme to pull the CSS directly from my website, while also using the same basic HTML architecture. When I preview a post now, it almost looks <em>exactly</em> like it will on my blog.</p>
<h2 id="whats-missing">What’s missing?</h2>
<p>I’d like a nicer editing interface. 1Writer is beautiful. I’d love it if either 1Writer got more powerful workflows, or if Editorial got a bit of a UI makeover. Either way, I’d be happy.</p>
<p>I’m also not crazy about the fact that my drafts live outside my blog repo. Even worse, drafts <em>continue</em> to live outside the context of my blog repo after I publish them. I’ll have to do some continual maintinence to keep my Editorial Dropbox folder clear of published drafts. It’d be nice if publishing a post would remove it from Editorial as well.</p>
<p>All in all, I think this is going to be really nice. I wrote (and published) this post using this workflow, and I’m super happy with it.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Caching Carthage con CircleCI</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/caching-carthage-con-circleci" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/caching-carthage-con-circleci</id>
    <published>2016-01-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Quitting</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/quitting" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/quitting</id>
    <published>2015-11-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the hardest things I’ve ever done is quitting smoking. I was never a two pack a day smoker, nor did I smoke for decades, but I was a regular 1/2 pack a day smoker for roughly 6 years (18 - 24). I also know that it’s something I am <em>still</em> addicted to, even though I’ve now quit about as long as I was an active smoker. I still have dreams about smoking, still have cigarette cravings, still have that deep <em>want</em> that doesn’t seem to go away. I’d love nothing more than to go back to smoking. Luckily, there are more important things that I’d rather do like lift weights and taste food. That’s enough to keep me from succumbing to my cravings.</p>
<p>My relationship with <em>alcohol</em> on the other hand, is a bit more… complicated.</p>
<p>Growing up, I was never a drinker. I dropped/got kicked out of college (a story for another time maybe), but not because I was partying (I wasn’t), I just wasn’t good at doing school. It actually wasn’t till I was out of school that I started drinking. But even then, I didn’t really <em>like</em> drinking, I just did it because other people did.</p>
<p>I moved from Texas to Massachusetts the week before my 21st birthday. Being in an unfamiliar environment, trying to meet new friends, alcohol became a way for me to socialize and meet people. I made some good friends, and drinking was just the thing we did. We’d get 40s of <a href="http://pabstbrewingco.com/blog/beer/st-ides/">St. Ides Malt Liquor</a>, get shitfaced, and watch Lost. We’d drink bottles of wine and watch foreign films. We’d drag my little brother (18 at the time) to the sketchy bar down the street and get plastered on Miller High Life (still maybe the worst hangover I’ve ever had). But that was OK, because hey, we were in school and young and partying out of control was the thing to do.</p>
<p>And holy shit, the drunk stories I acquired during that time. For example: I accidentally ran from the cops once. I was walking home drunk and they had reports of someone looking in cars with a flashlight. They stopped me, and when they went to their car I thought they left, so kept walking. About a block later I was surrounded by cop cars and having to answer questions. The cop in charge commented on my “thick Irish accent”, an obviously racist joke I didn’t actually get till like a week later.</p>
<p>Fast forward a few years, and I’ve fully embraced craft beer. I am drinking, and I enjoy it. I’ve become a hop-head and start looking for the hoppiest beers I can find. I collect beers, brew beers, read about beers. I’m a full blown beer snob. <a href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/one-year">My love for craft beers even led me down my current career path</a>.</p>
<p>And still I acquired stories. Turns out, I’m a fun drunk. I’m an extrovert where I’m normally introverted. I’m funny and I want to talk to people. People like me when I’m drunk. And I can <em>drink</em>, too. I can drink <em>a lot</em>. And so I don’t ever have to be the wet towel that has had enough, the one that needs to go home, the one that ends the night. I can be the last one standing every night.</p>
<p>A few years later and now I’m drinking bourbon. I <em>love</em> bourbon. All bourbon. I drink it straight, or maybe with a single ice cube. I love the bite of the bourbon, the smell, the sweetness. But, it hits me hard. Harder than beer. So something starts to change for me. I’m not just staying out all night anymore, I’m getting much drunker. I’m starting to act erratically, I’m starting to black out fairly regularly.</p>
<p>But hey, I’m still so much <em>fun</em> when I’m drunk. I’ve taken to stealing things when I’m drunk. Not anything serious, but I pick up things that are lying around me. Road cones, signs from hotel lobbies, that kind of thing. Everyone laughs, it’s hilarious, Gordon got drunk and stole another sign from the lobby, great stories.</p>
<hr />
<p>A couple of years ago I started noticing something that really bothered me. I had developed a reputation as a drinker. As <em>the</em> drinker. People make jokes and they mean well, but it starts to land differently. I have a slack notification set up for “beer” and people are using it to get my attention. We have “too much beer” in the office and I’m being counted on to get rid of it. These kinds of things become more and more frequent. Drinking has somehow become part of my identity. And that starts to make me wonder: am I in control here?</p>
<p>I push those questions down, as you do, and move forward. I keep drinking, I keep having fun, people keep liking me. But I’m also fighting with my wife about it more. I come home drunk, sometimes blackout drunk, she gets mad, I apologize, say it won’t happen again, rinse, repeat. I <em>know</em> I’m in control. I have to be in control. How could I not be in control?</p>
<p>So I decide to prove it to myself. I take a month off drinking. It surprises people. They can’t believe that <em>I</em>’m not drinking. But I just say things like “yeah, just taking a break for a while”. No big deal.</p>
<p>At the end of the month, I go back to drinking. I’m fun again. I’m the life of the party again. I’m blacking out again. I’m fighting with my wife again. I’m putting myself in danger again. I’m out of control again.</p>
<p>So I take a break again. See? I’m in control. No big deal. I don’t <em>have</em> to drink. Month ends, back on that horse. Getting blackout drunk and getting lost in New Orleans, missing a night of one of my best friend’s bachelor party. Getting blackout drunk and being too hungover to attend the end of a conference. Getting blackout drunk and stumbling a mile home in the dark and in the snow and sticking a good friend with an $80 Uber bill. Getting blackout drunk and causing my wife to stay up all night to make sure I’m still breathing.</p>
<p>This isn’t fun anymore. These stories aren’t funny anymore. This doesn’t work anymore.</p>
<hr />
<p>I don’t have a drinking problem the way most people think about drinking problems. I don’t get the shakes. I haven’t lost any jobs because I’ve shown up drunk. I’m not struggling keep away from the bottle. I don’t feel the need to avoid alcohol in every form at the risk of going on a bender.</p>
<p>But that doesn’t mean I don’t have a drinking problem. I’m incapable of saying no. I’m completely unable to walk away from drinking once it’s started. If I have 2 beers, I have 20. If I have one glass of bourbon, I have 10. <em>That</em> is my drinking problem.</p>
<p>So I’m not going to do it anymore. I’m not going to be the funny guy. I’m not going to be the life of the party. I’m not going to be the guy with the stories. But I’m also not going to be the guy apologizing to the people he loves. I’m not going to be the guy that misses things because he’s too hung over. I’m not going to be the guy that puts his life in danger. I’m not going to be the guy out of control.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, this is a relief for me. This is something that I don’t have to worry about anymore. It’s not a question that’s going to plague me every time I wake up after drinking too much.</p>
<p>Am I in control of alcohol? No.</p>
<p>If you want to talk about this (or if you need a DD) <a href="mailto:gordon@fonten.io">feel free to shoot me a line</a>.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Open Sourcing Tropos, Our iOS Weather App</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/open-sourcing-tropos" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/open-sourcing-tropos</id>
    <published>2015-06-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-06-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Weeks Nine and Ten</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-weeks-nine-and-ten" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-weeks-nine-and-ten</id>
    <published>2014-12-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Took me a little bit to get this written up, but I finished up weeks 9 and 10 of StrongLifts.</p>
<p>Week 9:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-9.PNG" />

</div>
<p>Whole bunch of milestones this week.</p>
<p>First up, I finally hit 135 on my overhead press, which means I’m up north of a full plate (45lbs on each side). This lift is really starting to push it for me. I’m happy that I’m finally over a full plate for all of my lifts, but I think I’ll start failing here before too long.</p>
<p>I also crossed the 300lb mark for Deadlift. I didn’t cross into 3 plates (315lbs) until the next week, but crossing over 300lbs means that I cross the arbitrary mark that I set for myself where I start using a switch grip instead of a double overhand grip for deadlifts. Next stop: 405.</p>
<p>Maybe the biggest victory for me this week was breaking the 250lb mark that I used as my 5 rep max back in week one. So that feels fairly major. I can’t say if my one rep max has jumped over the course of this program, but I feel like I have a <em>lot</em> left in the tank, even after crossing this milestone. So that’s probably a good sign. I think I should test my one rep max after these initial 12 weeks are over.</p>
<p>On the flip side of the coin, I started experiencing some knee pain in my right knee this week. I have <em>horrible</em> mobility in my hips and ankles. Always have. It’s something that I’ve been fighting against basically my entire life. On that 300lb deadlift, I noticed that my right knee was far from stable. Getting down into the starting position felt really shaky. I’ll come back to this in a bit.</p>
<p>This marks the (recorded) high watermark thus far, even though I’ve done another week since. I actually did another workout the following Tuesday, hitting 265 in my squat, but I missed the rest of the week, and so I ended up tossing the workout. Following the StrongLifts plan, I deloaded 10%, and came back for week 10:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-10.PNG" />

</div>
<p>Ok, so I didn’t deload <em>everything</em>. I didn’t want to drop back below 300 on deadlift. So there’s actually no record of me hitting 3 plates, instead it looks like I just jumped past 315 and went straight to 325. I still have enough room with this lift that I feel comfortable forging ahead.</p>
<p>The StrongLifts iOS app also added arm work this week. They… didn’t update their layout code unfortunately. The fact that those boxes are cropped in the screenshot wasn’t a mistake on my end, that’s just what it looks like on the device. Super fun.</p>
<p>The arm work adds 3x10 dips to the A workout (squat, bench, row), and 3x10 chinups to the B workout (squat, press, deadlift). The way you’re supposed to do it is max unbroken sets, up to 10 reps. Rest and repeat. I’ve been doing all 10 reps each set, but only scoring the unbroken ones. So for example, that 10/8/5 score on Thursday means I hit 10 unbroken, then 8, then 5. It was the only reasonable way I could think to score it.</p>
<p>The arm work is a real ego buster. I realized how much I suck at chinups today. It’ll be nice to watch this progress.</p>
<p>Following up my knee issues from earlier, I had a minor breakthrough with my squat stance on Thursday. I finally let myself widen my stance about another inch. This puts my feet just outside shoulder width, but also means that my feet don’t get knocked out to the side because of my poor mobility. That keeps my arches from collapsing, and prevents me from putting as much stress on my knees. It’s probably the most stable I’ve ever felt squatting before. I’m still going to fight for better mobility, but it’s nice to know that I don’t have to injure myself to keep progressing.</p>
<p>Like I said, with the exception of deadlifts, I deloaded everything by 10% for this week, so there aren’t really any big milestones here. Week 11 will look a lot like week 9 did, and then we’ll hit some new milestones during week 12.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Introduction to Function Currying in Swift</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/introduction-to-function-currying-in-swift" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/introduction-to-function-currying-in-swift</id>
    <published>2014-12-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-12-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Week Eight</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-eight" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-eight</id>
    <published>2014-11-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-8.jpg" />

</div>
<p>Things are heating up. I’m now 10lbs under what I started with as my 5 rep max for Squat. Still haven’t failed a rep. That’s almost certainly coming soon, though. The squats, and OH Press specifically are getting really spicy. I’ll hit 145 (full plates) on the OH Press tomorrow, actually, which will be a significant milestone.</p>
<p>Notice that I jumped 10lbs on squat between Wed and Sat, instead of the normal 5. That’s because I was at a new gym over Thanksgiving break, and could not for the life of me find 2.5lb plates. Finally found them because I wasn’t willing to jump that much for OH Press. One was on a random machine, and another was under a machine on the other side of the room. When I got home, I looked up how much a pair of 2.5lb plates from Rogue would cost. Seems like it might be worth the $8.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Week Seven</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-seven" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-seven</id>
    <published>2014-11-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-7.jpg" />

</div>
<p>This week’s milestone: 2 plates on Squat. That also means I’m now hitting my bodyweight for reps. I can see the weight starting to get pretty spicy over the next couple of weeks.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Week Six</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-six" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-six</id>
    <published>2014-11-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Crossed the 1/2 way point in StrongLifts on Sat.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-6.jpg" />

</div>
<p>Figured this would be a good point to figure out where I am.</p>
<p>When I started, I calculated my 5 rep max for each lift (Based on ~ 85% of my 1 rep max) as the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Squat: 250lbs (Based on 300lb)</li>
<li>Bench: 230lbs (Based on 250lb)</li>
<li>Row: 190lbs (Based on 225b)</li>
<li>Overhead Press: 150lbs (Based on 175lbs)</li>
<li>Deadlift: 370lbs (Based on 435lbs)</li>
</ul>
<p>That means as of Saturday, I’m working at the following percentages of my original 5RM:</p>
<ul>
<li>Squat: 84%</li>
<li>Bench: 67%</li>
<li>Row: 71%</li>
<li>Overhead Press: 76%</li>
<li>Deadlift: 71%</li>
</ul>
<p>This is totally in line with how I feel with these lifts. My squat is harder than the others by far, while the bench is the easiest.</p>
<p>If I’m able to continue this linear progression (doubtful), where would my working reps and estimated 1RM be in another 6 weeks? Squat and deadlift add 30lbs every 2 weeks, while all of the other lifts add 15:</p>
<ul>
<li>Squat: 300lbs working, 353lb estimated 1RM (53lb improvement)</li>
<li>Bench: 200lbs working, 235lb estimated 1RM (15lb loss)</li>
<li>Row: 180lbs working, 211lb estimated 1RM (14lb loss)</li>
<li>Overhead Press: 160lbs working, 188lb estimated 1RM (13lb improvement)</li>
<li>Deadlift: 355lbs, 417lb estimated 1RM (18lb loss)</li>
</ul>
<p>This isn’t totally accurate, since this math is pretty much bullshit, and a 5x5 working weight isn’t quite the same thing as a 5 rep max, but it’s interesting that most of these weights don’t ever even hit my previous maxes. Hard to tell if this means I should have started heavier for these lifts, or if I started too heavy on the squats and the OH press.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Week Five</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-five" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-five</id>
    <published>2014-11-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-5.jpg" />

</div>
<p>Went to a new gym today and couldn’t find the squat rack. Had to do my squats in a 3D Smith machine, which was a complete and utter waste of time. How the hell do people use those things? I couldn’t find info on how much the bar weighed, but I seriously doubt it was 45lbs. So that’s a fairly questionable 195 for today. I’m going to push ahead and do 200 on Monday because I’m not that worried about it, but it’s frustrating to feel like I wasted a workout.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Week Four</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-four" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-four</id>
    <published>2014-11-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A little late, but week 4 of StrongLifts. Finally got all of the lifts over 100lbs, and finally hit 2 plates on deadlift:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-4.jpg" />

</div>
<p>Last time, I said that I was worried that I was “too strong” for this program, which was both fairly arrogant, and also incorrect. My concern isn’t my strength, it’s that I’m outside of the “beginners gains” time frame. StrongLifts adds 5 lbs to each exercise every time you do it, which is an insanely fast progression. The weights are still light enough that it’s not hurting me yet, but I’m concerned about hitting a wall towards the end of the month. We’ll see though.</p>
<p>At the very least, it’s fun doing an actual structured program for once, and it’s great getting this much volume in, which wasn’t the case in CrossFit.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Weeks Two and Three</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-two-and-three" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-two-and-three</id>
    <published>2014-10-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-2.jpg" /> <img src="/images/StrongLifts/week-3.jpg" /></p>
<p>Weeks 2 and 3 of StrongLifts 5x5. Meant to post week 2 last week, but I totally forgot.</p>
<p>The weight for the squat is getting more respectable, but everything else is still insanely light. I’ve been finishing up my workouts with a 1k row on an erg machine just to get my heart rate up.</p>
<p>I’m starting to think I might be too strong for this program (#humblebrag). We’ll see how I feel a few weeks from now.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Functional Swift for Dealing with Optional Values</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/functional-swift-for-dealing-with-optional-values" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/functional-swift-for-dealing-with-optional-values</id>
    <published>2014-10-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StrongLifts Week One</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-one" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/stronglifts-week-one</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wrapped up the first week of StrongLifts 5x5 this morning. These weights felt super light, but I’m trying to stick with the program as it’s outlined. With this program, I should be adding 5lbs to each movement every time I do them, so (hopefully) it won’t be too long before the volume catches up. It really is fun squatting this much, and I’m excited to do deadlifts at least once a week, as opposed to the once a month I was doing them before.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="http://gordonfontenot.com/images/StrongLifts/week-1.jpg" />

</div>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Swift Sequences</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/swift-sequences" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/swift-sequences</id>
    <published>2014-06-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Test Driving iOS - A Primer</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/test-driving-ios-a-primer" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/test-driving-ios-a-primer</id>
    <published>2014-04-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Liftoff 1.0</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/liftoff-10" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/liftoff-10</id>
    <published>2014-03-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>One Year</title>
    <link href="http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/one-year" />
    <id>http://gordonfontenot.com/blog/one-year</id>
    <published>2013-09-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On March 23rd, 2010, I was in a bar with a couple of my friends. After a couple of beers, I began ranting about how I wanted an app on iPhone OS that could help me keep track of the beers I was drinking, along with tasting notes and ratings. It’s possible that I had maybe one beer too many, but when one of my friends suggested that I just build the app myself, I laughed it off and went on with my night. But when I woke up in the morning, it was still there in the back of my head. So on March 24th, 2010, I opened Xcode, started a project from a template, and started teaching myself Objective-C.</p>
<p>What I knew I’d get out of that project was a silly hobby that might make a few dollars. What I hoped for was a basic understanding about how to make applications, and maybe a nice challenge for weekend hacking. What I ended up with was a career change, and a newfound passion.</p>
<p>1 year ago today, I started as a professional iOS developer at <a href="http://www.thoughtbot.com">thoughtbot</a> in Boston, MA. In that past year, I have grown tenfold professionally. I started attending <a href="http://www.cocoaheadsboston.org/">my local CocoaHeads chapter</a> in January, and attended my <a href="http://nsnorth.ca/">first professional conference</a> in April. In June I attended my first <a href="https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/">WWDC</a> … <a href="http://altwwdc.com/">kinda</a>. And at the end of July, I started to <a href="http://buildphase.fm">co-host a podcast</a> with my good friend and colleague, <a href="https://twitter.com/hyperspacemark">Mark Adams</a>.</p>
<p>It’s been a hell of a fucking year. I’ve been almost unbelievably lucky over the past 12 months. <a href="http://www.thoughtbot.com/#our-team">My co-workers</a> are easily the smartest group of people I have ever met in my entire life. The projects I have been able to work on have been incredible learning experiences that have forced me to become a better developer on a daily basis. And for the first time in my life, I’m working in a job that I’m proud to call a career.</p>
<p>Can’t wait to see what happens next.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Designing for iOS: Blending Modes</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/designing-for-ios-blending-modes" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/designing-for-ios-blending-modes</id>
    <published>2013-03-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Opinionated Settings for App Development in Xcode</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/opinionated-settings-for-app-development-in-xcode" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/opinionated-settings-for-app-development-in-xcode</id>
    <published>2013-01-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Xcode Build Settings Part 1: Preprocessing</title>
    <link href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/xcode-build-settings-part-1-preprocessing" />
    <id>https://robots.thoughtbot.com/xcode-build-settings-part-1-preprocessing</id>
    <published>2012-11-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
